Negative. No sign.
نميبينمش
Wait a second. I think I got him.
صبر كن فكر كنم ديدمش
You know...
... ميدوني؟
...you could put someone's eye out with that thing.
...تو هم ميتوني از اون بالا بگري
We airlifted out the last passengers, Ace. We're heading out.
ما آخرين مسافر رو رسونديم.ديگه ميريم
What about the animal cargo?
پس اون حيوون چي؟
Don't worry. It's just one little raccoon. If I were you, I'd turn back.
اون فقط يه راكونه جاي تو بودم بر ميگشتم
If you were me, then I'd be you!
جاي من بودي پس من , تو بودم
And I'd use your body to get to the top!
و با بدن تو ميرفتم بالا
You can't stop me, no matter who you are!
نميتوني جلوي من رو بگيري
Loser!
بازنده
L-o-o-...
بازنــــــــــــده
...s-e-r.
بازنـــــــــــــــــــــده
Hungry, fella?
گشنه اي رفيق
That should hold you for a while.
حالا سير شدي
That's okay, Spike.
خوب اسپارك
There's nothing more we can do.
ديگه كاري نميتونيم بكنيم
Look, Spike!
ببين اسپارك
Do not fret, my woodland friend.
نترس دوست جنگلي من
Your life is in the hands of Ace Ventura...
زندگي تو در دستان ايس ونتوراس
...Pet Detective.
كارآگاه حيوانات
Whatever you do...
... هر كاري ميكني
...don't look down.
به پايين نگاه نكن
Hang on!
تحمل كن
Hang on, little buddy!
تحمل كن رفيق كوچولو
I got you!
گرفتمت
I think I got you!
فكر كنم گرفتمت
Maybe not.
شايد هم نه
You're slipping!
داري ليز ميخوري
Don't let go!
تسليم نشو
My goodness.
خداي من
Hello.
سلام
That was quite a shock.
يخورده ترسيدم
It's extremely nice to meet you.
خوشحالم كه ميبينمتون
My name is Fulton Greenwall...
اسم من فالتون گرينوال هست
...and I am looking for an Ace Ventura.
دنبال ايس ونتورا هستم
No man here...
همه مردان اينجا
...carries with him...
براي خودشون
...a label.
لقب دارن
What?
چي؟
Oh, yes.
آها بله
No names. How silly of me.
راهبان بدون اسم ,‌يادم نبود
He's an American.
آمريكاييه
We are all children...
... ما همه فرزندان
...of the same life force.
يك حيات هستيم
Yes, of course we are.
بله , البته كه هستيم
He bends over and speaks from his rear.
موهاش بلنده و تند حرف ميزنه
Oh, him.
آه ,‌اون
Right this way.
از اينور
He came to us a broken man.
اون شكسته خورده اومد پيشمون
He had lost the will to sustain his existence.
توي نجات يكي شكست خورده بود
Yes, I heard about that unfortunate accident with the raccoon.
بله شنيدم حادثه راكون
It was terrible for him.
براش وحشتناك بود
But the life force...
...ولي زندگي
...once again...
...دوباره...
...smiled upon him.
به اون خنديد
He's now...
حالا اون
...at peace.
در آرامشه
I will wait here.
من منتظر ميمونم
I must apologize.
عذر ميخوام
Quite. Well, no harm done.
جدي؟ , مهم نيست
Let me introduce myself.
معرفي ميكنم
My name is Fulton Greenwall, and I'm here to employ your services...
اسم من فالتون گرينوال هست اومدم تا از خدمات شما براي
...in the retrieval of a lost animal.
پيدا كردن يك حيوان استفاده كنم
Can you help us?
كمك ميكنيد؟
Your request is like your intestine.
درخواست شما مثل روده ميمونه
Stinky...
بد بو
...and dangerous.
و خطرناك
We can pay handsomely.
دستمزد خوبي ميديم
I am now a child of light.
من حالا فرزند نور هستم
Your earthly money holds no appeal to me.
پول زميني شما جذابيتي برام نداره
$20,000.
مبلغ 20/000 دلار
Really?
جدي؟
No.
نه
I cannot.
نميتونم
For I am sorely needed...
چون شديدا نياز دارم به
...here...
اينجا
...at the ashram.
به آشروم
May I interject?
ميتونم دخالت كنم؟
We're short of space.
ما فضاي كمي داريم
And it's important for you to use your talents.
و براي تو هم مهمه كه از استعدادت استفاده كني
Let me help you pack.
بزار كمك كنم ساكت رو ببندي
But I have yet to attain omnipresent super-galactic oneness.
ولي من هنوز به راز يگانه بودن دست پيدا نكردم
Wait!
صبر كن
There it is!
ايناهاش
You've just attained it.
ما دست پيدا كرديم
I have?
من؟
Just now.
بله
You are one!
تو يكي هستي
I can see it in your eyes.
توي چشمات ميبينم
You're more one than anyone.
تو از همه بيشتري
What about my medallion of spiritual accomplishment?
ولي مدال روحانيت رو هنوز نگرفتم
Take mine.
مال من رو بگير
This took you 80 years to achieve!
اين حاصل 80 سال عبادت توست
That's okay.
بيخيال
I don't like it anymore. Really.
مال تو
In light of this personal sacrifice you've made...
با اين فداكاري كه كردي
...l have no choice...
چاره اي ندارم
...but to take the case.
اين پرونده رو قبول مي كنم
Great!
عاليه
I'll tell the others.
ميرم به بقيه بگم
Master!
استاد
Break it to them gently.
جوري بگو ناراحت نشن
I've never seen them act like that before.
تا حالا اين رفتار رو ازشون نديده بودم
Denial can be an ugly thing.
اونها فقط عبادت مي كنند
We should go, Mr. Ventura. I've arranged a plane.
بريم آقاي وينتورا من برنامه پرواز رو ريختم
I'll meet you at the bottom.
پايين ميبينمت
There's still one more thing I must do before I go.
يه كار ناتموم دارم
Isn't this incredible?
شگفت انگيز نيست؟
It's going to be some kind of record!
يه ركورد زدم
"Everyone loves a Slinky
"......"
"You got to get a Slinky."
"......."
Go, Slinky, go!
"............."
Oh, man!
اوه پسر
Can you believe it?
باور ميكني؟
It was right there!
دقيقا همينجاست
Can I do it one more time?
يه بار ديگه انجام بدم؟
Forgive me, but if we don't hurry, we might miss the plane.
ببخشيد ولي پرواز رو از دست ميديم
Of course.
حتما
How selfish of me.
چقدر خودخواهم
Let's do all the things that you want to do.
هر كاري كه ميگي بكنيم
Canadian moose during mating season.
گوزن شمالي در حال جفت گيري
And now...
...حالا
...a yak.
گاو ميش
Peanut?
دودو؟
Yes, I have one right here!
بله.من يدونه دودول دارم
It's bulky, but I consider it a carryon.
بزرگه و مثل جنازه خوابيده
Peanuts?
دودو؟
Oh, I see!
آها گرفتم
If we can get back to business, Mr. Ventura?
برگرديم سر كارمون آقاي ونتورا؟
The Wachati are a peaceful tribe.
واچاتي قبيله زيباييه
Since their sacred animal has vanished...
حيوان مقدس اونها گم شده
...they believe that there is a curse fallen on their village.
اونها ميگن اين يه نفرينه
It all started some time ago when, one night....
... همه اينها وقتي شروع شد
So, the daughter of the Wachati chief...
دختر رئيس قبيله
...is set to wed the first son of the Wachootoo tribe.
آمادس تا با پسر رئيس قبيه واچوتو عروسي كنه
And the sacred animal was offered as dowry for the marriage.
و حيوان مقدس جهيزيه و پيشكش عروسيه
But...
...ولي
...if it is not recovered...
اگر پيدا نشه
...the result will be...
اونوقت
...the merciless slaughter of the Wachati.
واچوتو ها همه قبيله واتاچي رو ميكشن
Mr. Ventura?
آقاي وينتورا؟
There's...
... يه چيزي
...someone on the wing.
پرواز ميكرد
Some...
يه
...thing!
!چيزي
I'm sorry, what did you say?
ببخشيد چي ميگفتي؟
The daughter of the Wachati chief...
دختر رئيس قبيله
...is set to wed...
ميخواد ازدواج كنه
...the first son of the Wachootoo tribe.
با پسري از قبيله واچوتو
Spectacular!
تماشاييه
This land holds great beauty!
اين سرزمين زيباست
How far to the crime scene?
چقدر به صحنه جنايت مونده
I'm to bring you first to the consulate...
اول بايد بريم كنسولگري
...which is beyond the trees...
پشت درختان اين جنگل
...on the other side of the jungle. So, you'll have to circle around....
بايد جنگل رو دورش بزني
Steering's a bit loose!
يخورده مسير رو گم كردم
Alignment's off!
يخورده هم فرمون رو
"Oh, pretty Chitty Bang Bang
"..........."
"We love you
"........."
"And our pretty Chitty Chitty Bang Bang loves us, too
".............."
"On Chitty Chitty Bang Bang we depend
"..........."
"Chitty Chitty Bang Bang, our fine four-fendered friend."
"............."
There's the consulate!
كنسولگري اوناهاش
Oh, thank God!
اوه خدايا ممنون
If I can just find a parking spot....
جاي پارك داره؟
Perhaps we should slow down just a teensy bit.
بايد سرعت رو كم كنيم آقا
Nonsense, poopy pants!
ياوه نگو بابا
We're going a bit fast!
يخورده تند داريم ميريم
Really!
جدي
Look out!
مواظب باش
Like a glove!
مثل باقالي
You should get this baby detailed.
حال كردي؟
The Consul General's car!
ماشين ژنرال
Down!
بشين
Come on, man!
بيا
Mr. Ventura, so looking forward to your arrival.
آقاي ونتورا منتظرتون بوديم
Funny, it didn't seem that painful when you did it to the horse.
خنده داره درد داره
Sir...
قربان
...Mr. Ventura has an affinity for animals.
آقاي ونتورا يه دوستدار حيواناته
Shall we?
بريم
Shalln't we?
چرا نريم
Tell me, Mr. Ventura...
ببينم آقاي ونتورا
...just how good are you?
چقدر واردي؟
You're a workaholic.
تو الكلي هستي
You recently returned from a trip to Gotan, in Northern Africa...
تازگي از آفريقا اومدي
...and you just took a nasty spill because of some...
به خاطر كار بنائي
...shoddy masonry work.
حسابي كثيف و لجن شدي
Very impressive.
جالبه
May I ask how?
ميتونم بپرسم چطور؟
Surely.
حتما
The abrasion on your hand is the type sustained in a three-to-five foot fall.
خراش دستت به خاطر ده كيلو آجره
The remnants of plaster on your shoe pointed to a careless mason.
گچ روي كفشت هنوز مونده
Your new watch, a quality forgery, was...
ساعتت قلابيه
...most likely purchased through the North African black market!
بايد از بازار آفريقا خريده باشي
And my work habits?
مشروب رو از كجا فهميدي؟
A workaholic.
مشروب خور
The urine stain on your pants...
لكه شاش روي شلوارت
...would signify that you're a single-shaker!
دليل اينه كه انقدر خوردي
Far too busy for the follow-up jiggle.
كه تحمل نداشتي
Brilliant, Mr. Ventura!
با استعدادي ,‌آقاي ونتورا
Simply brilliant!
كاملا با استعداد
Spank you!
ممنونم
Spank you, very much!
قابل نداشت
We've been coexisting quite nicely with the native cultures...
ما با بوميهاي اينجا خيلي نزديكيم
...for the past 200 years. They're almost like family at this point.
نزديك 200 ساله مثل فاميل ميمونيم
Are they?
جدي؟
It is imperative that we recover the sacred animal.
بايد اون حيوان مقدس رو برگردونيم
If not, the peaceable Wachati will be obliterated.
وگرنه صلح واچاتي ها تموم ميشه
The Wachootoo are bloodthirsty.
واچوتو ها بيرحمن
They consider its disappearance both an insult and a curse.
ميزنند و ميكشند و فحش ميدن
Do I have something in my teeth?
چيزي تو دندونام هست؟
Cadby!
كابي
Lovely brunch, I must say.
غذاي دوست داشتني
Quinn!
كوئين
I'd like you to meet Ace Ventura.
با آقاي ايس ونتورا آشنا بشيد
This is Burton Quinn. He owns and operates Quinnland Safari Park.
ايشون بارتون كوئين هستند اون صاحب اين پارك تفريحيه
Most call me Quinn.
همه صدام ميكنند كوئين
Say hello, Tinky.
سلام كن تينكي
Pleasure, Tinky.
مخلصيم تينكي
Corvus corax. Common raven. Smartest of all birds.
كلاغ كاروكس كوچتر از مرغان مهاجر
Rare in these parts.
تو اين جاها كميابه
Excuse me.
ببخشيد
That's quite a wrap you're wearing.
عجب شالي پوشيدي
Perhaps I could get you some fluffy new slippers...
يه شال پوست جديد ميخواي؟
...made from the heads of innocent and defenseless baby seals!
از پوست يه  بچه خوك معصوم و بي گانه؟
Who is this ghastly man?
اين مرد گستاخ كيه؟
Ace Ventura, Pet Detective.
ايس ونتورا , كارآگاه حيوانات
You must be...
و تو بايد
...the Monopoly Guy!
مرد خاصي باشي
Thanks for the free parking.
از جاي پارك ممنونم
Another activist, Maguire.
يه طرفدار حيوانات ديگه
Activist, yes.
طرفدار , بله
Mr. Ventura...
اقاي ونتورا
...there's nothing wrong with enjoying the fruits of nature.
طبيعت مثل شرابه
You should try it some time.
از اين شراب استفاده كن
All righty, then.
باشه
You know something?
ميدوني؟
You're right.
راست ميگي
"Do not pass go. Do not collect two hundred dollars."
دو هزار دلار باختم
It's lovely, but I fancy myself an autumn.
من پائيز رو بيشتر دوست دارم
If you've quite finished, Mr. Ventura...
لطفا تموم كنيد ونتورا
...we might make for the projection room.
بايد به اتاق پروژكتور بيم
Kooky.
باشه
I'd like you to meet Hitu, chief of tribal security in the province.
با "هيتو" رئيس امنيتي استان آشنا بشيد
Please!
خواهش ميكنم
Don't...
لطفا
...get up.
پا نشو
At this point, we don't have any leads...
تا اينجا مشكلي نداشتيم
...but we've had similar problems in the past.
ولي بعد
Sorry.
ببخشيد
This is Derrick McCane...
اسم اين "دريك" هست
...spotted several times in the province in the past year. He makes a living...
چند وقت پيش ديده شد ... زندگيش رو از راه
...from rare and endangered species.
گونه هاي كمياب ميگزرونه
These two are Australians.
اين دوتا استراليايي هستن
The bald one is Mick Katie.
اون طاسه "ميك كتي" هست
The other is said to have been raised by aborigine--
اون يكي توسط بوميا بزرگ شده
Aborigines.
بومي
The natives call him--
بوميا بهش ميگن
Call him Gahjii...
بهش "گجي" ميگن
...the hunter.
شكارچيه
Both are known poachers and have been seen in the area!
هردوشون شكارچي هستن
This wedding's in four days. I cannot have bloodshed here!
چهار روز ديگه عروسيه نميتونم خونسرد باشم
We're counting on you!
من رو شما حساب كردم
Hi-ho, Silver!
اوناهاش
Away!
فرار كرد
I've assigned Greenwall to assist you.
ميگم "گرينوال" كمكت كنه
Before you go, Mr. Ventura...
قبل از اين كه بريد
...l'd like to show you something you may enjoy.
يه چيز جالب نشونتون ميدم
As one animal lover to another.
از يك عاشق حيوانات به ديگري
Something wrong, Mr. Ventura?
چيزي شده آقاي ونتورا؟
Of course not.
اصلا
It's a lovely room of death.
يك اتاق زيباي مرگ
Take care, now. Bye-bye, then.
Take care, now. Bye-bye, then.
Down, Boba!
بشين بوبا
Mr. Ventura, how could you?
آقاي ونتورا چطور ميتوني؟
Now, Mr. Ventura, I think the village is about a mile ahead.
آقاي ونتورا دهكده يك مايل جلوتره
Excellent.
عاليه
Flat tire!
لاستيكم
I think this joke has run its course, don't you?
اين شوخي قديمي نشده؟
Certainly.
البته
I prostrate myself before you and beg forgiveness.
گفتم حال كنيم
Don't get me wrong. I do enjoy the occasional prank.
بدم نمياد شوخي كنم
It's just that my heel is getting rather raw.
فقط پدر پام در اومد
We love you, Dark Continent! Good night!
دوستت داريم اقليم سياه
Listen!
گوش كن
The majestic song of the male silverback gorilla.
اين موزيك باشكوه يك گوريله
We should move along. It's their mating season and they can get rather hostile.
زودتر بريم فصل جفت گيريشونه و سريع عصباني ميشن
Excuse me, Mr. Ventura.
ببخشيد آقاي ونتورا
I have to rest.
بايد استراحت كنم
Of course you do!
البته كه ميتوني
The Wachati believe they draw their power from these caves.
واچاتي ها ميگن حيوون مقدس رو توي اين معدن گم كردن
Now they live in fear since their sacred bat has vanished.
اون خفاش خيلي مهمه
Bat?
خفاش؟
What...
كدوم
The one we're here to find, Mr. Ventura.
اوني كه دنبالشيم
You didn't say anything about a bat.
نگفتي اون خفاشه
What's the difference?
چه فرقي داره؟
Have you seen one? They're hideous.
خفاشها زشتن
Lifeless, beady eyes, clawed feet, huge grotesque wings. Even fangs.
چشماي براق , چنگال بالهاي ترسناك , دندونها
They give you rabies.
گازت ميگيرين
Yes, quite. I see your point.
آره
But are you saying that you won't take the case?
يعني پرونده رو قبول نميكني؟
No.
نه نميگم
As a being of light, I must show compassion for all living things.
يه راهب دوستدار همه موجوداته
Good.
خوبه
I'm not touching it, though!
ولي بهش دست نميزنم
No, spank you.
هرگز
The Wachati are a peaceful people.
واچاتي هاي مردمان خوبي هستن
They find all forms of life sacred.
زندگي مقدسي دارن
I like them already.
من هم ازشون خوشم مياد
Bumbawae Atuna.
"بومباوا آتونا"
Nice to see you.
خوشبختم
Ace Ventura, Pet Detective.
ايس ونتورا , كارآگاه حيوانات
How are you?
بعد از ظهر بخير
All righty, then.
Allrighty then
Excuse me.
ببخشيد
Your balls are showing.
تخمات افتاده بيرون
Bumblebee Tuna.
"بومباوا آتونا"
They have lived in the same state for thousands of years.
اونها هزاران سال اينطوري زندگي كردن
They did not know about disease until the white man came.
اونها مريض نميشدن تا سفيد پوستا اومدن
What's going on over here?
اونجا چيه؟
All young Wachati warriors must face five days...
مبارزان واچاتي بايد 5 روز اينجوري باشن
...of balance and concentration.
با تعادل
Should he lose his focus and fall...
اگر بيفتن
...he must start over again.
بايد از اول شروع كنن
Earthquake test!
تست زلزله
He's good.
خوبه
With my help, he could be the best.
با كمك من بهتر ميشه
We should see the chief, Mr. Ventura.
بايد رئيس رو ببينيم آقاي ونتورا
This way.
اينطرف
Neato!
بريم
The chief says he knew you would come.
رئيس ميگه ميدونست كه تو مياي
"Chim-chiminy chim-chim-cheroo!"
"Chim-chiminy chim-chim-cheroo!"
The chief has not understood the dialect you're using.
رئيس ميگه زبون تو رو نميفهمه
Say I'm happy to meet him.
بگو خوشحالم كه ديدمش
And that his sacred...
و به زودي اون
...bat...
... خفاش رو...
...is as good as found.
پيدا ميكنم
My goodness. The chief really seems to like you.
واي رئيس خيلي ازت خوشش اومده
That is a great sign of affection in the Wachati tribe.
توي واچاتي ها اين بزرگترين نشانه محبته
Really?
جدي؟
This is the chief's son, Ouda.
اين "اودا" پسر رئيسه
The missionaries came through and taught him English.
كمي انگليسي بلده
I like you!
ازت خوشم مياد
My....
ممنون
Aren't I the popular one?
چقدر محبوبم
Allow me to display my affection.
اجازه بديد محبت خودم رو نشون بدم
It is the mucus...
اين محبت چسبناك
...that binds us.
براي شما
The chief says that the sacred hut is over there.
رئيس ميگه خانه حيوان مقدس اينجاست
How'd they pass the guard?
دزدها چجوري نگهبان رو رد كردن؟
I'm afraid he was found shortly after...
كمي بعد از اين كه
...sleeping.
خوابيده
At ease, Soldier.
عيب نداره سرباز
We all make mistakes.
ما همه اشتباه ميكنيم
Quite an auspicious dwelling for a filthy, flying weasel.
خانه زيبا و آراميه براي يه جانور زشت
Please, Mr. Ventura!
خواهش ميكنم آقاي ونتورا
That is sacred ground. I'm sorry, but only the Wachati are allowed there.
اون منطقه مقدسه نبايد بري اونجا
Take it easy.
آروم
I'm the lougie guy, remember?
من دوست شما هستم
Yes, yes, Chief. Thank you.
بله رئيس ,‌ممنون
Thank you.
ممنون
The chief says that unless the sacred bat is returned...
رئيس ميگه فقط اگر خفاش مقدس قبل از
...before the marriage of the princess, the Wachati tribe will meet their death.
عروسي برگرده واچاتي ها از مرگ نجات پيدا ميكنيم
What type of bat are we talking about?
چه نوع خفاشي هست؟
The great white bat, of course.
خفاش بزرگ سفيد
Crepuscular Chiroptera?
خفاش روز زيست؟
But to the natives:
بله ولي بوميا ميگن
Shikaka.
شيكاكا
Shikasha!
شيكاشا
Shish kebab.
شيك كباب
Shawshank Redemption.
Shawshank Redemption.
Chicago!
شيكاگو
You're out of there!
تو باختي
Go on. You're gone. Go on!
باختي,‌برو بيرون
Were you going to eat these?
اين رو ميخوري؟
I've got to inspect that cage.
بايد از كلبه آمار بگيرم
My, my, my.
م م م
This fruit paste is delicious!
اين شيره ميوه خوشمزس
The pottery is lovely!
سفالگريتون هم خوبه
It's made from guano.
با چلغوز درست شده
Guano?
چلغوز؟
That sounds so familiar.
آشناس
Bat droppings.
مدفوع خفاش
It's a chief resource of the Wachati. They use it to make things.
واچاتي ها از اين همه چيز درست ميكنن
Yummy!
خوشمزس
Now this is really fascinating. This is a great Wachati tradition.
اين قسمت زيباست زيباترين رسم واچاتي ها
The virgin's dance of seduction.
رقص تازه عروس
I am now a holy man.
من يك مرد مقدسم
I think of women only as mothers of our children.
زنان فقط مادر بچه ها هستند
They are a sanctuary for the reproductive organs.
آنها جايگاه مقدس تولد هستند
A temple to house the miracle of procreation.
در معبد بهشون ميگن معجزه تولد
Do you have $1?
يه دلار شاباش داري؟
Thank you so much!
خيلي ممنون
I've not danced in years!
من سالها نرقصيدم
Hi.
سلام
Don't mind me.
خودت رو ناراحت نكن
Sleep.
بخواب
Fe...Fi!
Fe...Fi!
Fo...fum!
Fo...fum!
I smell the fingerprints of scum!
بوي اثر انگشت مياد
Better dust the place.
بزار گرد و خاك كنم
Totally clean.
كاملا تميز
Not one damn clue.
حتي يك سرنخ نيست
Unless....
به جز
Here she comes. Oh, boy.
اوه پسر داره مياد
Holy, holy, holy, holy.
يا مقدس , يا مقدس
Good thoughts in, bad thoughts out.
فكر خوب داخل ,‌فكر بد بيرون
You have come to help us.
تو اومدي كمكمون كني
We are in...
ما خيلي
...great appreciation.
ازت ممنونيم
You...
... تو
...speak English.
انگليسي بلدي؟
Yes!
بله
The missionaries came with books.
از كتاب
You are very good with that!
خيلي خوب ميزني
It's incredibly accurate.
خيلي حال ميده
Care to try?
سعي نميكني؟
Not bad!
بد نبود
Try again. Relax your shoulders.
دوباره , بدن آروم
Breathe.
نفس بكش
And release.
رها كن
There you go!
عالي بود
You make me smile.
تو من رو ميخندوني
And yet...
ولي
...l am troubled.
من در ذجرم
You see...
ميدوني؟
...the man my father wants me to marry...
مردي كه پدرم برام انتخاب كرده
...l am worried I will not please him.
ميترسم ازش خوشم نياد
I've never known a man.
هيجوقت مردان رو نشناختم
I'd love to help.
ميخوام كمك كنم
But you see...
ولي
...l have vowed to take a life of celibacy.
قسم خوردم باكره بمونم
Well....
خوب
Perhaps this...
شايد اين
...will assist your decision.
تصميمت رو عوض كنه
Those are very nice.
اونها خيلي نازن
But I am a child of light. A pure spirit.
ولي من فرزند نورم ,‌يك روح پاك
I'm no longer encumbered by sexual appetites.
ديگه رغبت سكس ندارم
Oh, mama, oh, mama...
واي ماما ,‌واي ماما
I'm so sorry, Mr. Ventura....
ببخشيد آقاي ونتورا
That's okay.
چيزي نيست
I was just...
فقط دارم
...practicing my mantra.
عبادت ميكنم
Didn't you want to visit the sacred caves?
معدن رو نميبيني؟
I do!
باشه
Meet me outside in ten minutes.
ده دقيقه ديگه ميام
If I don't finish my meditation...
اگر عبادتم تموم نشه
...l tend to get a little cranky.
يخورده بد اخلاق ميشم
Take care, now. Bye-bye, then.
Take care, now. Bye-bye, then.
Everything here seems good! Big load off my mind!
عاليه
You can speculate all you want, but unless you check it out yourself...
ولي تا خودت نري ببيني
...you never know.
هيچي نميفهمي
Let's go back.
برو ببين
Don't you think you should investigate?
فكر نميكني خودت بايد تحقيق كني؟
There's no reason to go in there. Ever.
الان فصل رفتن به اونجا نيست
I sense it as a holy man.
من يه مرد مقدسم
-You said you wanted-- -It's dark!
خودت گفتي - تاريكه -
I could fall into a precipice.
ممكنه بيفتم تو چاله
Take this.
اينو بگير
Spank you, Helpy Helperton.
ممنونم , كمك كوني
I am not afraid!
من نميترسم
I really like it here.
واقعا از اينجا خوشم مياد
My medallion!
مدالم
I will fear no living creature...
از هيچ موجود زنده اي نميترسم
...as long as I keep this near me.
تا وقتي اين رو دارم
Take that, you winged spawn of Satan!
بگيريد تخم شيطونها
That's okay.
عيب نداره
All I really need is my torch.
من فقط اين مشعل رو ميخوام
Die, devil bird!
بسوزيد شياطين
I'm okay.
حالم خوبه
They're in my hair!
رو موهام
God in heaven! Help me!
خداي بهشت
There is nothing in your hair.
هيچي رو موهات نيست
Exactly.
دقيقا
I was merely running a drill.
تمرين دويدن ميكردم
Just as I suspected.
همون طور كه انتظار داشتم
Quinn.
كوئين
What?
چي؟
We met him at Cadby's soirée.
تو شب مهموني ديديمش
His bird is a raven, Tinky. I found that inside the cave.
اون يه كلاغ داشت تو كلبه مقدس هم يدونه ديدم
You don't understand. Burton Quinn is a powerful man.
كوئين مرد قدرتمنديه
Worry not.
نگران نباش
For l...
... چون من
...am a master...
...ارباب...
...of disguises.
پنهان شدنم
Eat up, guys!
شما بخوريد
None of this animal goes to waste.
اينا كاملا تازه هستن
Mr. McCane.
آقاي مك كن
How're you?
چطوريد؟
I'm doing well.
عالي
Don't mind me, Mr. Quinn.
بيخيال من
I'm just a curious little rhino.
من فقط يه كرگردن كنجكاوم
I appreciate your...
ممنونم
...agreeing to undertake this.
كه قبول كرديد
Meeting secretly with sinister types much?
ملاقات محرمانه و خيلي شيطاني
Ah, not too much. Ah, much too much.
خيلي نه ,‌خيلي خيلي
Kind of hot in these rhinos.
توي اين كرگردن خيلي گرمه
Warm!
گرمه
I had a dog and his name was...
من به اين ميگم
...Bingo!
بينگو
Time to get some oxygen.
وقتشه يكم اكسيژن بگيرم
Come on!
زود باش
Mayday!
پيام اضطراري
Must...
بايد
...have...
هوا
...air!
بگيرم
Come on!
زود باشيد
Quiet, quiet, quiet. Look, look.
آروم ,‌آروم , ببينيد , ببينيد
Oh, look!
اوه ببينيد
The mother rhino is giving birth!
كرگردن مادر بچه به دنيا مياره
Oh, God.
اوه خدا
Mommy!
مامان
Cool!
باهال بود
We have to get out of here!
بايد از اينجا بريم
Quick, get in the jeep.
ساكت برو تو ماشين
Quick, girls, get in!
زود باشيد دخترا ,‌سريعتر
Welcome to Quinnland.
به سرزمين كوئين خوش آمديد
And you, too, my friend.
تو هم همينطور دوست من
I know, you'll be happy here.
مطمئنم خوشت مياد
How did you get out, fella?
چجوري اومدي بيرون؟
You're a cute little devil.
شيطون كوچولو
What you got?
اون چيه داري؟
Where's the bat?
خفاش كجاست؟
What's this about?
يعني چي؟
Who are you?
تو كي هستي؟
Where...
...بگو
...is...
... خفاش ...
...the bat?
كجاست
I know who you are.
من ميشناسمت
I met you at Cadby's!
تو مهموني ديدمت
You're that...
تو همون
...Ventura fella!
ونتورا هستي
Last chance!
اخرين فرصت
Where is that darn bat?
خفاش لعنتي كجاست
What're you going to do?
ميخواي چيكار كني؟
Whatever I have to get some answers.
بايد ازت جواب بگيرم
Stop!
بس كن
Stop it!
تمومش كن
You'd like me to stop it.
ميخواي تموم كنم؟
Getting to you?
چرا بهش پول دادي؟
I won't tell you anything.
هيچي بهت نميگم
A tough guy, huh?
پررويي آره؟
I know what to do with tough guys.
ميدونم با آدمهاي پررو چيكار كنم
My brother used to do that!
برادرم هميشه اين كار رو ميكرد
You sadistic bastard!
حرومزاده ساديسمي
Stop it!
بسته
All right! I'll talk!
باشه ميگم
Spill it!
بگو
I paid Derrick McCane to find the bat.
من فقط به ژنرال پول دادم تا خفاش رو پيدا كنه
I thought it could be an attraction.
براي افزايش گردشگر ها
Business has been a bit off lately.
به خاطر كاسبي
So...
پس
...you don't know who...
...نميدوني كي خفاش...
...took the bat?
رو دزديده؟
Neither does McCane.
هيچي
I'm going to untie you now.
من بازت ميكنم
Before I do, I want you to know that I'm really...
ولي قبلش بايد بگم جدا
...truly...
واقعا
...very...
خيلي
...sorry!
ببخشيــــــــــــــــــــــــــــــــد
Appreciate the lift!
تشكر بلند و بالايي بود
We'll walk from here.
از اينجا پياده ميرم
Quinn is out of the picture. We have no more suspects or clues.
ديگه هيچ مظنون يا كليدي نداريم
But I have instincts.
ولي من غريزه دارم
And my instincts tell me we're getting closer.
و غريزه من ميگه نزديك شديم
I can feel it.
ميتونم احساس كنم
I can feel it like it's right...
... حس ميكنم دقيقا توي
...in my neck!
گردنمه...
Run!
فرار
Starting to get numb!
داره بي حس ميشه
Three darts...
...سه تا دارت
...is too much!
خيلي زياده ....
I think...
... فكر كنم
...l lost them!
گمشون كردم ....
Flowers...
.. گل براي
...for me?
منه؟...
I do declare, Mr. Beauregard.
واي داري چيكار ميكني؟
You are my hero.
تو قهرمان مني
Was l...
... من توي
...talking in my sleep?
خواب حرف زدم؟ ...
You've been suffering hysteria. It's a natural reaction to the poison.
حمله عصبي داري اين واكنش طبيعيه ذهره
Water.
آب
Guano bowls.
كاسه چلغوز
Collect the whole set.
همش رو خوردم
Ace, did you see the shooter?
ديدي كي شليك كرد؟
Only their feet.
فقط چنگالشون
Not enough for a positive ID.
نتونستم ببينم
It's the dart of a Wachootoo shaman.
اين دارت كاهن هاي واچوتوهاست
The whaty whatan?
كي؟
The Wachootoo shaman, or medicine man, has protested the intertribal wedding.
كاهن واچوتوها به ازدواج بين قبايل اعتراض داره
Has he?
جدي؟
You do not speak Wachootoo.
ولي تو نميتوني واچوتويي صحبت كني
I go with you.
من هم ميام
Ouda will be my interpreter.
كوادو مترجم منه
Please, take care.
لطفا مواظب باش
The Wachootoo are savages. If they catch you, they'll be merciless.
واچوتوها وحشي هستن اگر بگيرنت رحم نميكنن
Worry not.
نگران نباش
I will be as a fly on the wall, a grain of salt in the ocean.
من فرار ميكنم مثل نمك توي اقيانوس
I will slip amongst them like a transparent...
مثل يه چيز نامرئي
...thing.
پنهان ميشم
The sacred bat must be in a hut.
خفاش بايد توي چادرها باش
We'll never know until I can walk freely among them.
تا وقتي كه بين اونها نريم نميفهميم
Wunderbar!
خودشه
He exclaimed with great relish.
من چقدر باهوشم
Come on, girls, show them what you got.
بياين دخترا , ببينم چي بلدين
I'm sure it's fine.
مشكلي نداره
Ouda is probably going for help right now.
كوادو به زودي بمياد كمك
Hello, Ace!
سلام ايس
They found me!
اونها پيدام كردن
No sweat!
بدون زحمت
Don't beat yourself up.
خسته نباشي
You know...
ميدوني ...
...gingivitis is the No.1 cause of all tooth decay.
عصبانيت دليل اصلي پوسيدگي دندانهاست
What does equinsu ocha mean?
اين سفيد دندون چي ميگه؟
White devil.
شيطان سفيد
Tell him I'm not.
بگو من نيستم
I only met you. How do I know?
از كجا بدونم
-He said-- -Let me guess. "White devil"?
اون ميگه - حدث ميزنم: ‌شيطان سفيد -
You speak Wachootoo?
كلمه واچاچويي ياد گرفتي؟
Tell them what I'm saying:
:بهشون بگو
I come in peace!
من با صلح اومدم
I couldn't help but notice the equinsu ocha part.
من يك كلمه واچوچويي بلدم
Did you refer to me as "White Devil"?
من رو شيطان سفيد گفتي؟
That's how they know you.
اونها اينطوري ميشناسنت
Leave that part out from now on.
اين قسمت رو ديگه نگو
I represent the princess!
من فرستاده صلحم
"...is hell."
يعني جهنم
The last thing we want...
ما هيچ وقت
...is a fight.
نميگيم جنگ
The chief said...
رئيس ميگه
...if you pass all Wachootoo tests...
اگر همه تستهاي واچوچو ها رو رد كني
...you do not die.
نميميري
Kooky.
عشقه
My entrance to the winner's circle!
ميخواين جايزه بدين؟
Your admiration is well-founded, but I'm merely a servant.
شما لطف داريد ولي من چيزي نيستم
Do not worship me!
من رو پرستش نكنيد
Chief says you have passed all tests but one.
رئيس ميگه همه تستها رو رد كردي ولي
Only left is Wachootoo Circle of Death.
دايره مرگ مونده
Funny...
بامزس
...that's my specialty.
مخصوص منه
This is it?
اينه؟
I have to beat him?
اين رو بايد بزنم؟
All righty, then!
All righty, then!
I must tell you...
... بايد بگم
...l don't wish to fight.
...نميخوام بجنگم.
Violence is no longer in my nature...
خشونت ديگه تو طبيعت يه راهب نيست
...but if you want it, you got it, sister.
ولي اگه ميخواي باشه خواهر
Biting, I see.
گاز ميگيري؟
I was unaware that the Wachootoo...
نميدونستم واچوتوها
...were biters!
گاز ميگرن
Why don't you try this on and see how it fits?
پس اين رو تست كن
He much better fighter than you.
اون خيلي از تو قويتره
Doi!
جدي؟
All right!
باشه
This White Devil thing has gone far enough.
شوخي بسته
Nobody...
... هيچ كس
...messes...
شوخي نميكنه
...with the "do"!
با موهام
He said, sorry, White Devil...
اون ميگه متاسفم
...but he must kill you.
ولي بايد بكشمت
I'll have you know I have the reflexes of a cat.
من عكس العمل گربه
And the speed of a mongoose.
و سرعت ميمون رو دارم
Throw it!
بنداز
I dare you!
زود باش
Ouda, don't just stand there. Throw me a spear!
اونطور نگاه نكن نيزه بنداز
It's in the bone! It's in the bone!
رفت تو استخون
He says you make him laugh.
اون ميگه تو خندونديش
You are like sissy girl!
مثل دختر بچه ها ميموني
Wachootoo Chief say, "You friend to Wachootoo."
رئيس ميگه تو دوست واچوتو ها هستي
But if the curse of Shikaka not lifted by tomorrow's sun at top of sky...
ولي اگر قبل از طلوع آفتاب شيكاكا پيدا نشه
...Wachootoo kill all Wachati and smash your head on a rock.
واچوتو همه واچاتي ها رو ميكشه و سرت رو با سنگ ميشكنه
Super.
لطف دارين
Take care, now. Bye-bye, then.
Take care, now. Bye-bye, then.
Take care, now. Super. Bye-bye, then.
Take care, now. Super. Bye-bye, then.
Are your legs sore?
پاهات زخم شد؟
Want me to carry you?
ميخواي گريه كنم؟
That won't be necessary.
لازم نيست
I have a high pain threshold.
من تحمل بالايي دارم
Ace, why you stopped?
چي شده؟
The Wachootoo didn't take Shikaka.
واچوتو ها شيكاكا رو ندزديدن
Hi, welcome back.
سلام خسته نباشي
What would you say this is?
اين چيه؟
Dart of Wachootoo shaman.
دارت كاهن واچوتوها
Precisely.
دقيقا
And when compared to one of the darts that hit me before?
و در مقايسه با دارتهاي قبلي
Same.
يكسان
Only to the untrained eye.
با چشم معمولي بله
The Wachootoo dart is made of wood from a mimosa tree...
دارت واچوتوها با چوب درخت ابريشم درست شده
...while the other is carved from a red fungus-bearing acalla.
ولي اون يكي با سماروغ قرمز
And there's only one area of the jungle with red...
و فقط يك جاي جنگل هست كه
...fungus-bearing acallas.
سماروغ قرمز داره
Go back to the village.
برگرد به دهكده
Tell them the Wachootoos attack tomorrow at noon.
بگو واچوتوها صبح فردا حمله ميكنن
This little hound dog just picked up a scent.
اين سگ شكاري يه رد بو جا گذاشته
Won't be long now, Katie.
طول نميكشه عزيزم
Big night tonight.
امشب شب بزرگيه
You're going to meet your new owner.
با صاحب جديدت آشنا ميشي
G'day.
آره
Disgusting rat!
موش حال به هم زن
Gravy!
خودشه
Did you hear that?
شنيدي؟
What is it?
چي بود؟
Silverback.
گوريل
Female.
ماده
Big.
بزرگ
About 200 meters...
نزديك 200 متر
...south.
به جنوب
We'd get $5,000 for one of those.
ما 5000 دلار ميفروشيمش
-What about the rat? -Don't worry about it.
موش چي- نگران نباش-
We'll be back in no time.
زود برميگرديم
Stay downwind of it.
در جهت باد
You're even uglier than I thought.
از اوني كه فكر ميكردم زشت تري
She's a big one, isn't she?
خيلي بزرگه نه؟
Oh, boy.
اوه پسر
Deciduous trees on the bank.
قايقي از تنه درخت
Suman shrubs with extreme protococcus.
توت فرنگي
Steadily increasing water current.
جريان آب
Spike...
اسپيلك
...l think we could assume the stream gets pretty rough up ahead.
فكر كنم جريان آب تا حدي خشن ميره
As soon as I get you loose, you can chew through my ropes.
تو رو شل كنم ميتوني طناب رو گاز بگيري
That's it!
خودشه
Yes. Your turn.
نوبت توئه
All right!
خوبه
I'm alive!
من زندم
Say "uncle"! Say "uncle"!
بگو عمو ,  بگو عمو
Don't start what you can't finish!
كاري نكن كه نتوني
Quit hitting yourself!
خودت رو بزن
Oh, water tastes good, yes!
تست زير آبي
This isn't over yet.
هنوز تموم نشده
There's something I missed. Some clue or motive I've overlooked.
يه چيزي رو نميفهمم انگيزه
And that motive is...
انگيزه چيه؟
...plah!
...plah!
Think!
فكر كن
Someone wants the tribes to destroy each other.
يكي ميخواد: قبايل همديگه رو نابود كنن
There must be something valuable in this equation.
يه چيز با ارزشي وجود داره
Perhaps we should meditate, Spike.
عبادتگاه كمك ميكنه
For it is said that when seeking answers, one must...
وقتي سوالي داري
...quiet the soul in order to hear them.
بايد ساكت باشي و روحت بشنوه
What is it the Wachati possess...
واچاتي چي داره
...that is of great value to other men...
كه براي دزد با ارزشه
...besides the princess with the amazing rack?
به غير از اون پرينسس با اون چيزاش
All righty, then.
All righty, then.
You're back?
تو برگشتي؟
You can dispense with the smallpox, all-knowing one.
تو همه چيز رو ميدوني
I'm here on business, and time is of the essence.
من به نتيجه كارم نزديكم
Very well.
عاليه
What answer do you seek?
چه جوابي ميخواي؟
What do the Wachati possess...
واچاتي چي داره
...that is of great value to civilized man?
كه براي دزد با ارزشه
The medallion will lead you to the answer.
مدال تو رو به جواب ميرسونه
You do still have the medallion, don't you?
تو مدال رو داري درسته؟
Medallion?
مدال؟
Why, surely.
بله ,‌يعني
I left it back...
گذاشتمش
...with my body.
پيش بدنم
Your aura...
ايمانت
...is weakening.
سست شده
Okay! I threw it in a cave!
خوب بابا ,‌انداختمش توي معدن
What do you want from me? What are you? Mr. Perfect?
حالا كه چي؟ آقاي كامل
Where is it?
ميدوني اون چيه؟
It's probably lying...
خالي بنديه
...in a big pile of....
يه تيكه
Guano!
چلغوزه
They have guano!
اونها چلغوز دارن
Like...
مثل
...a glove.
يه تيكه چلغوز
Hi, Chief!
سلام رئيس
Appreciate your meeting me here.
خوشحالم ديدمت
Let's go kick some...
بريم دهن
...consulate butt.
كنسولگري رو سرويس كنيم
Hello, Ace.
سلام ايس
You want your money?
پولت رو ميخواي؟
Wrong again, Sweeney Toad.
اشتباه كردي غورباغه
I've come for the sacred bat. Where is it?
دنبال خفاش مقدس اومدم ,‌كجاست؟
Why...
چي؟
...whatever can you mean?
منظورت چيه؟
Guano!
كوانو
Hello!
سلام
Does "poop" ring a bell?
زدم تو خال؟
"Guano mines as a source of nitrate...
معدن كوانو
"...producing 84 percent of the world's fertilizer...
نزديك 84 درصد كود جهانه
"...a $1.4 billion industry."
يك صنعت 14 بيليوني
That's what this war is about.
اين جنگ واسه معدنه
You can't take possession of the caves while the Wachati inhabit the area.
نميتوني صاحب معدن بشي تا وقتي واتاچي ها اونجان
And you want that dookie so bad...
و تو نميتوني
...you can taste it.
اونجا رو مزه كني
I thought that--
فكر ميكردم
Yes, thank you, Fulton.
ساكت فالتون
That's a fine theory, Mr. Ventura.
تئوري خوبيه آقاي ونتورا
What's it got to do with me?
از كجا فهميدي؟
I thought you'd...
گفته بودم
...never ask.
هيچ وقت نپرس
When I met you, there was a white substance on your shoe.
اون روز يه چيز سفيد رو كفشات بود
Yesterday, I saw the same substance outside the hut...
...امروز مشابه اون رو تو كلبه ديدم كه
...and it hit me that the Great White Bat has white guano.
من رو ياد چلغوز و مدفوع خفاش سفيد انداخت
That's what you slipped in! It was on your shoe!
اشكال كارت اينجا بود روي كفشت
And that explains the abrasion on your palm!
و اون خراش روي دستت
Let me run that back for you.
از اول ميگم
That's what you slipped in! It was on your shoe!
اوني كه دستت رو خش انداخت
And that explains the abrasion on your palm!
رو كفشت خرابكاري كرد
Damn, I'm good!
لعنتي , من كارم درسته
Can you feel that?
حسش ميكني؟
...Captain Compost?
كاپيتان كود
The day of redemption is at hand!
امرزو روز رستگاريه
Repent!
توبه كن
And thou shall be saved.
توبه كن شايد نجات پيدا كني
Very good.
عاليه
I believe you've solved the case.
اين پرونده رو حل كردي
One thing I still don't understand, Mr. Belvedere.
يه چيزي رو نفهميدم
If you are the slime behind this little flim-flam...
اگر تو پشت اين ماجرايي
...why, oh, why...
چرا , چرا
...did you hire me?
من رو استخدام كردي؟
I'm afraid there'll be an investigation after the war.
ترسيدم بعد از جنگ بيان تحقيق
You were my alibi...
تو دليل مني
...to prove I'd done everything I could to stop it.
كه من تلاش كردم اونها نجنگن
Arrest him.
بازداشتش كن
Please arrest him.
لطفا بازداشتش كن
Simon says, "Arrest him."
اون رو بازداشت كن
I thought you loved all animals, Mr. Ventura.
تو كه حيوونات رو دوست داشتي آقاي ونتورا
Shall I stick him on the wall?
بچسبونمش به ديوار؟
No, I don't think it'll be necessary, Gahjii.
فكر نكنم لازم باشه
Mr. Ventura has very cleverly stolen the sacred bat of the Wachati.
آقاي ونتورا خيلي زيركانه پرونده رو بست
Unfortunately, we were unable to recover it in time to stop the war.
ولي ديگه نميشه جلوي جنگ رو گرفت
Hit the lights!
چراغ رو روشن كن
The switch is on the wall beside you! Go for it!
كليد روي ديواره بزنش
Flick it!
قطعش كن
All righty, then.
All righty, then.
Shall we go to jail?
بايد بريم زندان؟
What are you? H.R. Shove-n-Stuff?
چيه قهرمان پرتابي؟
Get in!
برو تو
Just one more thing.
فقط يه چيزي مونده
What are you doing?
چيكار ميكني؟
Stop it!
بس كن
I said, stop it!
گفتم بس كن
To the jungle, Boba!
به سمت جنگل بابو
Friends...
... دوستان
...rodents...
...جوندگان...
...quadrupeds!
...چهار پايان
Lend me your ears!
گوش كنيد
Imbecile! You let him get away!
احمق , گذاشتي فرار كنه
You don't seem to understand. The tribe will be killed.
قربان نميفهميد؟ قبيله كشته ميشه
Remind me to send a sympathy card.
يادم بنداز كارت همدردي بفرستم
We're going to get the bastard.
بريم بگيريمش
There's nothing he can do now.
اون هيچ كاري نميتونه بكنه
We've got the bat, and it's nearly noon.
ما خفاش رو داريم
What the hell's going on?
چه خبره؟
You see...
... ميبيني
...humans and animals can live in harmony!
انسان و حيوان ميتونن با هم زندگي كنن
Sorry for the delay, Ace.
ببخشيد كه ديركردم ايس
Hey, Poachers!
ببخشيد شكارچي
Say hello...
سلام كن به
...to my stinky little friend!
دوست من استينك
Get out! Get out!
برو بيرون برو بيرون
Not so fast, Sally!
سريع نيستي
Get it away!
ببرش اونور
He wants to go off-road.
از جاده ميري بيرون
Nobody wants to play with me.
چرا كسي باهام بازي نميكنه
Loser!
بازنده
From the consulate, right?
تو از  كنسولگري آره؟
This is weird.
جالبه
Noon.
صبح
The Wachati.
واچاتي ها
The spirit will overcome.
روح غلبه ميكنه
Headhunters!
شكارچيان سر
Shikaka!
شيكــــــــــــــــاكــــــــــــــــــــــــــــــــــا
Coming through. Clear a path, people!
كار آگاه حيوانات وارد ميشود ,‌راه رو باز كنيد
They will now consummate the marriage as the tribe watches.
حالا اونها يگانگي قبيله ها رو محكم ميكنند
Well done, Ace.
عالي بود ايس
You must be extremely proud.
تو بايد مغرور باشي
Pride is an abomination.
غرور كار حراميه
One must forego the self...
يكي بايد به
...to attain spiritual creaminess...
روحانيت كامل برسه
...and avoid the chewy chunks...
و از پستي ها
...of degradation.
دوري كنه
What'd he say?
چي ميگه؟
I think he's saying, "She's not a virgin."
فكر كنم ميگه: اون باكره نيست
They can tell that?
حق داره
Sincronizado por Avengers Usando SubTune 1.2 2002 Bs As Argentina
By kamran_dotnet@yahoo.com